Saionji-sensei.
Please get some rest.
I'm fine.
More like, I can't afford to sleep now!
Let's go
get some fresh air.
We're taking a break.
Sure.
Go ahead.
You guys should get some rest too.
Please call me if anything comes up.
Tonight is the deadline.
Let's go.
Daikichi!
It's so hot.
Feels like ice.
You're too cold.
If I turn the AC off, the guys will ruin the work material with their sweat.
I've heard your body temperature can drop due to stress too.
That new job you were talking about...
I don't think it's worth dropping the quality of your work.
Ma-chan, you're not strong in body or spirit.
Besides, you're earning enough as it is,
so you don't have to be greedy.
But...
What?
I'm earning enough for now,
but I'm not so sure about next year.
There are a lot of youngsters showing up in the field.
I might be surpassed in the blink of an eye.
Ma-chan, you're over-thinking it in a bad way.
It's not good for your body.
You've got ink on your face again.
Sheesh.
You're a girl, you know?
I'm not a girl!
I'm a manga artist!
I'm going back to work!
Sorry about that.
Jeez...
Going to work is such a pain!
Good morning.
I called for you earlier.
Sorry.
It's so hot.
Do you feel better like that?
Yeah.
We should probably make lunch.
Yeah!
Hey, come here and help!
Okay!
Rin's summer vacation has started.
We make her lunch in the morning,
and then she goes to a student day care.
How about visiting Grandpa's grave next Saturday?
It's almost time for O-bon,
TL note: O-bon is a festival to honor your ancestors.
and it's also-
What, you don't want to?
The bellflowers haven't bloomed yet.
They might need a little more time.
We can buy some from a florist for now,
and go again when the ones we're growing have bloomed.
Okay.
Grandpa would be happy if we use the bellflowers you've been caring for.
He would, wouldn't he?
But what would make him the happiest is you being there.
That's the most important thing.
Right. I understand.
If Rin weren't here, I probably wouldn't be thinking about Grandpa.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun!
I can't do it if you keep moving!
Sorry!
Besides, why is your hair so thin?
Don't know!
What's wrong?
Just a second!
Hey, we're going to be late!
What's up with him?
Daikichi, how many more days?
Summer Evening Bon Odori Festival
About 10 days, I guess.
Found one!
A cicada skin!
Skin?
This brings back memories.
I've got quite a few in here.
That's gross!
Don't shake it!
You're going to be late!
Hey!
Watch out for cars!
I've been here many times.
With Grandpa?
Yeah.
I see.
Grandma's grave is here too, right?
Grandpa's grandma?
No, mine.
Let's see... My mom is Grandpa and Grandma's kid,
and I'm her son.
She's Grandpa's daughter?
But that would mean she's my sister.
Shit! I've steered the conversation in a bad direction!
Over here!
It's over here!
Kaga Family Grave
It's all wet.
That jar...
Masako-san had one too.
What the hell? She didn't even go to the funeral!
Rin, I'll be right back.
Just wait here for a while.
Pull out the weeds!
Okay!
What should I do?
Besides, what's she doing, visiting his grave with another guy?
Woof!
What is it?
Why are you here?
I almost mistook you for someone dangerous.
I'm here to visit his grave.
It's not really a big deal, but I thought I should let you know.
Rin is there too.
At Grandpa's grave.
Um, I...
Rin's important to me, but I don't think of you often, to be honest.
I don't care about your circumstances either.
Unless Rin wants to,
I have no intention of letting you meet her.
I know that!
What are you trying to say, after following me out here?
Would you at least like to see her in secret?
We're going to clean the grave, light some incense, and go home.
It'll probably take a while, so...
Rin's waiting for me.
Do what you want! We'll just mind our work!
Rin, sorry about that.
I kept you waiting.
Um...
Are you okay?
Um, I just had to...
Nothing. I'm sorry.
Were you waiting?
Not really.
Were you lonely?
You're weird.
Why are you so flustered?
I'm not weird.
Here.
Thanks.
Put it on that side.
Okay!
She's not a baby anymore.
Being related to someone is incredible.
It is, isn't it?
She looks just like you!
That back...
She's pretty cute.
Their intimacy...
He's just like Souichi-san.
I'm glad.
That surprised me.
Sure, O-bon is just around the corner, but this was a coincidence.
That girl... She turned seven today.
I see.
Your daughter did surprise me,
but I thought that guy was your ex-boyfriend.
Of course not.
That man has no brains at all.
Although I can't tell what he'll be like after another half-century.
Half... century?
That man...
On the surface, he seems to be her boyfriend.
Daikichi, you know...
Well, I won't say it's wrong.
Daikichi!
I guess there are people in this world who can find lovers quickly.
Daikichi, I said!
Yes!
Can we go to Grandpa's house?
It's pretty close, right?
That place isn't Grandpa's anymore.
Is there someone living there?
No, not at the moment,
but it belongs to my uncle... my mom's brother now.
The family altar is there too.
I see.
It can't be helped.
If it's just going into the garden, I can ask my uncle.
Really?
Only the garden, okay?
Okay!
I know the way there!
I'm going to take that job after all.
Seriously?
Are you sure that's okay, Ma-chan?
I've decided to work alone.
I need to work more.
You're working plenty hard!
More than other people, that's for sure.
It's not enough.
I need to work so hard that I don't remember what I ate the last day.
Something like that...
I forget that all the time.
If I don't do that...
If I don't forget these memories, I...
Just a little more!
Kaga
It hasn't changed at all.
You've completely changed, though.
They're gone!
The bellflowers!
The soil is gone too!
Those bellflowers were important to Grandpa.
I'm sure he didn't mean to get rid of them.
My uncle knows that they're Grandpa's favorite flower, at least.
But they wither up during winter,
and they're not guaranteed to blossom when spring comes again.
Also, these stones...
If you don't spread them out like this,
weeds will pop up and would be a pain to deal with.
I'm glad I took Rin's fragrant olive tree from here.
It escaped intact.
But...
I'm glad we took Grandpa's bellflower plant home.
Thanks to that, it was saved!
Right!
Change may not be so bad after all.
That grave will always be Grandpa's, okay?
Okay!
Rin!
Happy birthday.
On the cake: Happy birthday, Rin-chan!
It's a chocolate one!
Saionji-sensei, please check these one last time.
Are you okay?
It looks pretty impossible this time around.
Once you say it, you really won't be able to do it, so don't!
Go ahead.
I'll finish it for sure.
Daikichi! The festival stalls are going to close!
No, they won't.
Sounds like Grandpa.
Kouki-kun is here.
What's wrong? Weren't we supposed to meet at the shrine?
My mom's running late again.
How come you're not wearing a yukata?
I can't jump if I'm wearing one!
Incredible, right?
Where's your mom?
She has to put on her yukata, so she'll meet us there.
Let's go! The stalls are going to close!
Daikichi! Watch out for cars!
I know!
Wait up! It's hard to run wearing wooden slippers!
I'll carry you.
No way!
Carry me instead.